# Nicholas Le

Product Design / Graphic Design

Working within product design for the past few years has allowed me to practice design thinking as well as polish my graphic design skills. I'm hoping to apply my design experience to improve products that I love.

nicksle @ berkeley.edu nkle.co (951) 729-0566

## Education

## **University of California, Berkeley**

2015 - 2019

**B.A.** — Molecular and Cellular Biology

Certificate in Design Innovation

# **Experience**

#### **CERTAIN LENDING**

Design Intern

Oct 2018 - Dec 2018

Collaborated with the engineering team to define a new company identity, and worked to create a uniform design system to work in.

Collaborated with the engineering team on the main dashboard user experience; analyzing user's movements within the web application to make core design decision.

Created print and digital media assets using Illustrator to be used for marketing, product, and in-house.

#### THE SMALL AND MEDIUM BUSINESS EXCHANGE

Product Design Intern

July 2018 - Oct 2018

Collaborated with head designer to identify main user painpoints within the user flow of the mobile app, and worked to ideate solutions.

Redesigned the confirmation pages for successfull bids, buys, and sells of bonds focusing on creating a user experience focused on earning users trust.

## **UCB STUDENT AFFAIRS COMMUNICATIONS**

Graphic Design Assistant

Oct 2017 - Aug 2018

Designed graphic components to increase awareness of various Facebook and Twitter campaigns for the Public Service Center.

Designed infographics following the UC Berkeley style guide to increase awareness of the impact the Public Service Center has had on the campus.

## **UCB INNOVATIVE DESIGN**

Design Consulant

Aug 2017 - Present

Participated in weekly client consultation meetings in which I questioned representatives as to what design components their clubs need.

Designed multiple iterations of designs for 4 different oncampus clubs that ranged from logos to physical banners which increased campus awareness of these clubs and their events.

Collaborated with several group members to complete UI/UX case studies using user ethnography techniques and tools such as Sketch and Origami.

# **Software Proficiency**

**Adobe Illustrator** 

**Adobe Photoshop** 

**Adobe After Effects** 

**Adobe XD** 

Sketch

InVision + InVision Studio

## **Relevant Coursework**

User Experience Design (DES INV 190)
Visual Communication (MS 101)
Evaluation of Evidence (SOC 5)
Introduction to Data Science (CS 8)
Introduction to Media Studies (MS 10)
Startup Lab (IEOR 185)
Industrial Design and Human Factors (IEOR 170)

# **Skills**

#### **User Research**

Comfortable with conducting user interviews and performing secondary research.

### **UI/UX Design**

Able to make deductions from user research to ideate and implement features or compositional designs to improve user experience.

## **Interaction Design**

Comfortable with wireframing and rapid prototyping to identify optimal user flows and interactions.

## Front-End Web Development

Able to use HTML, CSS, JavaScript as well as frameworks such as jQuery to create web sites.